This video demonstrates how to perform a front-of-the-eye examination using the anterior segment loop of the Arclight device.
Start with hand hygiene and introduce yourself.
Confirm the identity of the patient, explain the examination and gain consent to perform it.
Initially take a few seconds to observe both eyes at the same time.
Look at the periorbitor, eyelids and eyes, commenting on any swelling,
redness and discharge, as well as prominence of the eyes or
abnormal eyelid position.
Then perform a magnified examination using the arclight.
Switch on the white light and hold the device close to your eye.
Slowly approach
the patient's right eye first until it is in focus.
This will be at around 6
centimeters.
Ask the patient to move their eye outwards and inwards, then up and down,
while gently holding their eyelids.
Systematically noting the different
structures seen, thinking of them in groups.
The first group includes the upper
and lower eyelashes and lid margins.
The second includes a conjunctiva and sclera and the lower
forenicks.
The third group is the cornea.
The junction of this was a sclera called olimbus
and the pupil, surrounded by the iris.
Once you have finished noting all these structures,
move on to assessing the anterior chamber depth.
The anterior chamber is the space between the
cornea and the iris.
By shining the light from the temporal side, the depths of the
anterior chamber can be assessed.
A shadow on the nasal iris can suggest a
shallow anterior chamber.
This is a normal examination with no shadow.
Now select
the blue light on the arc light.
With fluorescing dye, the tear film, areas of
epithelial loss and disease will be highlighted.
The dye fluoresces brightly
with the blue light.
Recording a diagram, the sight and size of areas of epithelial
the loss and disease.
Finish by examining the superior tarsal plate.
Place a cotton
bud on the upper lid, then gently lift the lashes upwards while slowly pressing downwards
with the bud.
Initially observe with a naked eye, then bring in the arc light for a magnified
view.
Repeat this examination on the other eye.
Afterwards thank the patient, summarizing
the records of findings and repeat hand hygiene.
Please have a look at our other University
the Andrews Arc Light Project Videos.